Hey, janitor.
Take out my golf club bag.
Okay, sure, sir.
-Make it quick!
-I'm coming!
He's frustratingly slow.
-What's going on?
-What happened?
Mr. Kim In-su?
You can't leave yet.
You should see our chief doctor first.
Please come follow me.
Excuse me.
Sir.
I'm sorry, but this is a hospital,
so smoking is prohibited on the premises.
Oh, I see. I'm sorry.
Well--
Sir, I can take the cigarette butt. Here.
Goodness, no. It's okay.
Don't worry about it.
Okay, then.
Well, have a great day, sir.
Sure.
"Sir"?
JASEONG NURSING CARE CENTER
LAWYER OH HYUN-CHANG
Mr. Oh!
I've been thinking
and decided to check with you.
I heard Geu-ru's uncle is a murderer.
It can't be true, can it?
Where did you hear that?
OMG.
Is it true?
Oh my goodness. I can't believe this.
Where I heard doesn't matter.
What was he thinking?
How could he leave Geu-ru to a murderer?
Can a murderer be a guardian?
Isn't it against the law?
If you knew all this,
why didn't you stop Uncle Jeong-u?
What kind of lawyer are you?
Aren't you supposed
to protect your clients?
I'm done.
To be exact, Mr. Cho is not a murderer.
He nearly killed an opponent in a game,
but the victim didn't die.
So he wasn't punished for manslaughter.
As far as I know, there's no reason
to see him as a threat to Geu-ru.
Did something happen
that I don't know about?
No, but--
Has Mr. Cho put Geu-ru in danger
or threatened him?
Shit.
I felt like he has, but…
not really.
Has he caused any inconvenience
or harm for Geu-ru?
Somehow I felt like he has,
but not really.
Has he done any harm to Move to Heaven
by inappropriate behaviors?
It seems like he has all the time,
but not really.
Na-mu, what if you didn't hear
that Mr. Cho was a murderer?
I still don't like him,
but I wouldn't be scared of him either.
Still, there's one thing
I don't understand.
Aren't you worried
even if knowing all that?
No, I'm not.
How come?
Geu-ru has this good tree called Na-mu.
Have a good day.
What are you doing here?
We got no job today.
That's how a useless newbie's mind works.
What?
A helpful staff like me knows better.
I'm here to do prep work,
check the devices,
and work on marketing strategies
although we got no job.
It's called taking ownership.
I wouldn't say it's for our company,
but what I can tell is
just a little cheap excuse
to stick around Geu-ru all day long.
"All day long"?
Mom!
What does he mean by that?
I don't get it.
Aren't you studying for the exam?
Did you lie to me?
Actually, you know--
It's not like I--
How do you do?
I should've introduced myself sooner.
I am Geu-ru's uncle.
You must be Na-mu's mother.
I'm also sorry for the late introduction.
There seems to be a misunderstanding.
I was only joking.
Since I just moved in,
I'm not doing a good job
with Geu-ru and the work.
So Na-mu is worried all day long,
and that's what I meant by it.
Oh, is that so?
She may be young, but she's very bright.
I've been wondering whom she takes after.
Now that I see it is you.
People say my Na-mu is
a chip off the old block, me.
I won't bother her as much
since she studies for something important.
I apologize for that.
You don't need to.
-Na-mu.
-Yes?
You got to go to study now.
Yes, that's right.
Okay. From now on,
stop bothering me, and be good to Geu-ru.
I don't want to worry anymore.
Oh no, I'm late. Mom, I have to go now.
Man, even good-for-nothing can be useful.
It looks like he isn't too bad after all.
-Okay, have a good day.
-Sure.
Uncle!
-Uncle!
-What is it?
We got a deposit for a job,
but I don't recall getting a request.
I don't understand.
What do you mean?
Oh, I remember now. I received the call.
Three days ago.
And he requested to come on the 1st.
Oh no. It's today. Darn it.
-Is it today?
-Yes.
He asked to come today.
We got nothing else to do,
so we can do it, right?
Since I joined you,
it seems like orders have flooded in.
Not orders. They're requests.
We say "order" when ordering chicken.
And when Dad was here,
we had three times more requests than now.
Something is wrong. Na-mu isn't here yet.
We must ask her to come.
Or else, she'll be mad again.
No need.
Na-mu will be on leave
from Move to Heaven for a while.
For a personal reason.
Your call cannot be connected--
Let's go up there first.
Hello.
We're from Move to Heaven.
Is nobody home?
Shit.
Call the police now.
WE'RE LEAVING THIS WORLD TOGETHER
WE APOLOGIZE TO THE ONES
WHO CAME TO CLEAN UP AFTER US
Hi, Geu-ru.
-Hello.
-Yes, hello.
-It must've been shocking.
-It caught me off guard.
By the way, what happened?
When did you say you got this request?
Three days ago, a man called
-saying his name was--
-Mr. Kim In-su.
-Are you sure it was Mr. Kim In-su?
-Yes.
Why?
One of the deceased is named
Kim In-su, the husband.
That means he requested himself
when he was alive.
What?
He decided to leave for good
before he called you.
This is a social worker
from the ward office.
How do you do?
I'm Son U-rim, a social worker.
I was in charge of these two.
Mrs. Lee Mi-seon was a long-term patient
at a nursing home,
and Mr. Kim In-su was a janitor
at an apartment complex.
After I heard the news, I found out
that he was fired a month ago.
I think that was a trigger
to make this decision.
Shit.
Is something wrong?
Decision? A decision to do what?
To drag his sick wife out of the hospital
and drug her and himself to death?
If you wanted to kill yourself,
just do it alone. What was he thinking?
She didn't deserve this!
Do you think it's easy for the elderly
to decide to end their lives at their age?
What's not easy about it?
To make the call on someone else's life
and call it responsibility?
It's the same as a murder.
A double suicide? How do we know
that she agreed to this?
Got a smoke?
I left it in the van.
I'm going for a smoke.
We don't have anyone's number
who can receive their belongings.
Do you know any?
They don't have any family members.
I'm afraid there seems to be no one
who can take their belongings.
Still, we will organize them.
Don't pay a silent tribute or any shit
to a man like him.
Don't try your best.
Just give a lick and a promise.
A loser like him won't go to heaven,
so don't even pray for him.
I was told not to say carelessly
when you don't know their stories.
Okay.
I guess your wonderful dad said that.
Anyway, I won't clean
a speck of dust in there. Understand?
Okay, then,
today's pay will be deducted
from your monthly salary.
Hey, don't be so quick to--
-I'd like to give you a hand if it's okay.
-Sure.
Gosh, darn it.
Mr. Kim In-su and Mrs. Lee Mi-seon,
you passed away on May 31st, 2020.
I'm Han Geu-ru, a trauma cleaner
from Move to Heaven.
I'll now begin to help you
with your final move,
Mr. Kim In-su and Mrs. Lee Mi-seon.
IN APPRECIATION OF KIM IN-SU
THE LATE KIM IN-SU & LEE MI-SEON
REST IN PEACE
Uh?
But you said--
We need to finish
before the truck guy gets here.
It's not that I changed my mind.
It's just that I didn't want
to get an earful from him.
-Understand?
-I understand.
Still, you'll only get
33 % of today's pay.
Whoa, now I can see
that you're such a heartless,
cold-blooded, penny-pincher boss.
I have a heart
and warm blood like everybody else.
My blood type is A.
And as for penny-pincher…
I'm not sure what that means.
Forget it.
So we're done
when taking these out, right?
Man, it's suffocating.
Hey, let's open the window.
It's the rooftop floor,
so no one can see us like in an apartment.
We can open the window, right?
Shoot, it's stuffy in here.
What's that?
A door?
Geu-ru. Han Geu-ru.
You need to see this.
Oh my!
What's all this?
Wow.
Does this look to you like something made
by an evil man who killed his good wife?
I couldn't care less.
Two of us are looking at the same thing,
but one sees love
while the other sees hate.
Do you want to bet?
At least this shows the world I believe,
and I'll make sure you see that.
Hello?
See what?
Gosh, it's going to take forever
to clean these out.
They look fine.
Maybe we can take and sell them?
No, we can't.
We have to return them.
How? We don't know where they're from.
We have to go to Block 105.
Block 105?
There are so many Block 105s out there.
Don't be ridiculous.
Let's clean these out and leave.
Gosh, there are so many.
BLOCK 105, WOOHYEONG APARTMENT
Right there.
We must go to Block 105
of Woohyeong Apartment.
Hey, are you really going to take them
to the apartment there?
I'm leaving without you.
I mean it!
Is this Jaseong Nursing Care Center?
I called you earlier about--
Yes, I'm going there now.
Okay.
Hey, there.
Get in.
Sorry?
Or not.
WOOHYEONG
Who is it?
I'm here to return your plant.
What?
It's the plant we threw away.
-What a hassle.
-Thank you.
He passed away on May 31st, 2020.
Why did you bring it back
from the dead man?
It brings bad luck.
I'm here to return your plant.
No, thank you.
Mr. Kim In-su passed away
on May 31st, 2020.
Mr. Kim--
Mr. Kim passed away? Are you sure?
Yes.
Oh, poor Mr. Kim.
Mr. Kim, would you please come out?
Okay.
What is it?
Ta-da!
It's an air conditioner for your office.
Oh my goodness, Min-ji.
I don't understand.
I raised the money with my friends.
I was still short, but my parents
gave allowance for my birthday in advance.
Do you like it? Your office will be cool.
Did you really get this for me?
For my office?
Hang on a second.
Hey, kid. Who says you could do that?
Sorry?
I bought this with my money, sir.
An air conditioner doesn't run on its own.
Who's going to pay for the electricity?
You?
It won't cost much.
How do you know if it won't cost much?
Sir, please calm down.
I'll use it for a moment only on hot days.
How can I trust you?
Humans tend to seek comfort and luxury
if they can afford it.
And what's with you, really?
If it's too hot,
buy and use it with your own money
and take it with you when you leave.
You expect us to get you the AC unit
and pay for the electricity as well?
Are you a beggar or something?
You're crossing the line a bit, sir.
I'm not anywhere near the line!
As you expect to get help for everything,
you end up where you are, being a janitor.
You should be ashamed
and turn down this little girl's help.
Okay, I understand.
I won't use the air conditioner.
Mr. Kim!
Use fans instead.
Two fans will be good enough.
It's okay.
I still appreciate your gesture.
Okay? Thank you.
Yeah.
What?
-Do you know this place?
-Sorry?
You didn't bother to use the GPS.
Ah, that.
Aren't you getting out?
Hold on.
-Now that you're here, stay put.
-What for?
You need to wait and hear
the truth of Mr. Kim In-su.
Okay, let's suppose I misunderstood him.
What would you want me to do?
Say sorry to you?
Of course, you should.
Not to me, but to Mr. Kim.
Have you heard
of defamation of the deceased?
What now?
Don't go anywhere, okay?
What's with her?
Sang-gu.
I heard you got out.
I'm sorry.
How have you been doing?
You tell me.
Thanks to you, we can keep Su-cheol alive
when he's supposed to be dead already.
I should say thank you,
but I can't bring myself to say it.
I'm sorry.
You'll know if you stick around here
what it's like
to be in a living death.
What happened?
He's not dead,
but he's not alive either.
His brain is too damaged.
He probably won't wake up.
If he is not dead,
it means he breathes and his heart beats.
-Without consciousness.
-You fucking bitch.
It's all your fault.
He was laughing
and talking with me till yesterday.
If you didn't set us up like this--
God damn it.
Don't blame me. How can it be my fault?
I told you to fight, not to kill him.
If Su-cheol dies,
I won't let you die easily, either.
Are you sure you can handle it?
Bring him back no matter what.
The sleeping pills they took were
the ones Mrs. Lee got here.
She probably has saved them for long.
She always said her wish was to die
a day before her husband dies.
And as for Mr. Kim,
he had terminal pancreatic cancer.
Gosh.
Mr. Kim In-su?
You can't leave yet.
You should see our chief doctor first.
Come follow me.
NOTICE OF DISMISSAL
What brings you here at this hour?
Nothing.
Just to see you.
Is everything okay?
Sure. Plus, I have good news.
I came here to grant your wish.
Well, now…
let's go home.
Really?
Goodness.
I got no time for this.
I should prepare
their portraits for the funeral.
Wait.
-Are they the deceased earlier?
-Yes.
Why do you ask?
Excuse me, sir.
Have a great day, sir.
Shall we?
What's going to happen to them?
I mean their funeral and so on.
Since they have no family,
they're classified as unattended deaths.
Luckily, the city offers funerals
for people without a family,
so we'll give a small one for them.
Good to hear.
THE LATE KIM IN-SU & LEE MI-SEON
REST IN PEACE
Geu-ru, you need to give up this time.
There's no one
you can hand over this box to.
How did you deal
with a situation like this before?
I heard Uncle Jeong-u
burned it separately.
Then that's how we do it this time.
Han Geu-ru.
It's time to move on.
-Goodness.
-No!
Not yet!
Come on.
You really don't know how to say yes.
You'd better let it go. Come on.
I wish there's anybody close to them.
I wish I can find anybody who knows them
and pays a visit to their funeral.
That would be wonderful,
but you also heard there was no one.
There isn't even a number to call.
What can we do?
Geu-ru, come back here!
Uncle Sang-gu!
All right, Geu-ru.
We'll find them after the funeral, okay?
You need to get ready for the funeral.
You're going, right?
As you said,
they'd be lonely if no one shows up.
So, you shouldn't be late either.
Okay?
JISAN FUNERAL HALL
THE LATE KIM IN-SU, THE LATE LEE MI-SEON
These are the flowers
Mr. Kim took care of for Mrs. Lee.
ASTER: PRECIOUS MEMORIES
GLOBE AMARANTH: UNCHANGING LOVE
ROYAL AZALEA: JOY OF LOVE
HYACINTH: HUMBLE LOVE
Aster.
Precious memories.
Peace lily.
Thoughtful love.
Dracaena.
Keeping a promise.
Dwarf umbrella tree.
Luck and love.
Lily.
Pure love.
Globe amaranth.
Unchanging love.
Iris.
Joyful news.
Camellia.
I love you.
Camellia means "I love you."
in the flower language.
Mr. Kim taught me that.
Min-ji!
Mr. Kim, Min-ji is here.
Wow, I don't know who the deceased is,
but the family must be pretty affluent.
It's the executive's mother
at Jaehwa construction.
-Really?
-That VIP hall.
I see.
JAEHWA CONSTRUCTION LABOR UNION
REST IN PEACE
It's a th-- thief! There's a thief!
-You idiot!
-Thief!
Shoot.
Gosh.
Taking someone's stuff
without their consent is theft.
It's a criminal act.
I'm not stealing it.
I'm just borrowing it temporarily.
I was going to return it tomorrow morning.
Still, it's wrong.
Hey, take a look around.
We have nothing,
but they have too many
to put them all together.
Nobody will notice even if one is missing.
They'll probably
throw them away in the end, you know.
Do we really need a wreath?
I wouldn't say we must have it,
but it'd be sad if we don't have any.
Why would it be sad?
Think about it.
It's like a card saying
there's someone who wishes
the deceased would reach heaven safely.
-Still, taking someone's stuff--
-All right.
I won't take it. Are you happy now?
Man, nobody would notice
even if I took one.
You're being too inflexible.
REST IN PEACE, JAEHWA
JAEHWA CONSTRUCTION
JAEHWA FOUNDATION
1998, JAEHWA
SENIOR MANAGER KIM IN-SU
1989, JAEHWA CONSTRUCTION
MANAGER KIM IN-SU
1981, JAEHWA CONSTRUCTION
KIM IN-SU
-I found them.
-Found what now?
People who knew Mr. Kim
and can come to his funeral.
They're here.
Geu-ru!
Assistant Manager Kim In-su from 1981.
He's at Hall Five now.
-Do you know him?
-Of course, I don't.
This business card looks archaic.
The company logo was so tacky.
You weren't even born in 1981, were you?
-Senior Manager--
-You can't do this here. Please leave.
I'm sorry.
-You can't do that in here. Stop it.
-Wait.
Who did you say he was?
Senior Manager Kim In-su from 1998.
He's in Hall Five right now.
Senior Manager Kim In-su, you said?
Yes, sir.
Well,
when I was still
a working-level associate,
Senior Manager Kim was always there.
I promise
KIM IN-SU
JAEHWA CONSTRUCTION
I'll keep this name card for a long time.
See you again.
How beautiful it is
To look at someone from the back
Who confidently knows
it's their time to leave
My love that endured
A season of passion in spring is falling
Blossoms fall everywhere
I am surrounded
by the blessings of farewell
And now it's time to leave
Toward an exuberant forest
And to autumn
when trees begin to bear fruit
My youth
Dies like a flower does
You lived a tough life.
Please rest in peace,
Mr. Kim and Mrs. Lee.
You deserve it.
Wait!
Thank you.
Sorry?
I've never been proud like I was today
when holding a funeral
for those without family.
All thanks to Move to Heaven.
Okay.
Good work.
Goodness.
They're pink.
What?
Uncle, your ears turn pink.
What are you talking about, kid?
Gosh.
It happens when your capillary vessels
suddenly expand
because your heart starts beating faster.
That little-- Hey! It's nothing like that!
Wreath delivery.
A wreath?
You must be mistaken.
There's no one who'd send it here.
I got the right address.
MOVE TO HEAVEN, REST IN PEACE
Didn't you say we don't need a wreath?
As you said,
it'd be sad not to receive any card
from someone who wishes
they'd arrive at heaven safely.
There are many people
who wish Mr. Kim In-su
and Mrs. Lee Mi-seon reach heaven well.
So I sent a card on our behalf.
-What's this?
-It's one of the plants Mr. Kim had.
So what's got to do with me?
Ms. Son U-rim, the social worker,
asked me to give it to you.
You should take care of it from now.
I hate taking care of anything.
Handling you is already too much.
This is called dahlias.
"Happy to know about your heart."
-What?
-That's what dahlias means.
"Happy to know about your heart."
I--
Right.
Shoot.
SU-JIN
Yes, Su-jin.
Su-cheol is--
he's in critical condition!
Okay, I'll be right there.
INTENSIVE CARE UNIT
Subtitle translation by: Jean S. Kim